

MUJTABA SHAFIQUE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Hello! My name is Mujtaba Shafique and I am a software engineer with 1+ years of experience in commercial website design and development. My main expertise is in MERN stack development.

I'm looking for a great enthusiastic developer team to work for that will provide me with challenging, interesting work that I can learn from and contribute to. I would like to contribute more to website development, Front-End in React and Back-End in NodeJS or Spring Boot(Java) with MongoDB and MySQL DB. Currently learning ReactNative.

CONTACT ME AT

- +923046511650
- mujtaba.shafique@outlook.com
- https://mujtaba-ali.vercel.app
- https://github.com/Mujtaba4li
- in linkedin.com/in/mujtaba-shafique
- Isamabad, Pakistan

EDUCATION

Capital University of Science and Technology (CUST)

BS Software Engineering | 2018 - Aug 2022

- Heavy focus on full-stack engineering with modules on front-end and back-end processes.
- Built a POS web application in ReactJS as front-end and SpringBoot as Backend with MySQL database as a semester project.
- Smart car parking system (IoT Project) as a semester project with Arduino UNO
- Our FYP is a "No Poverty" donation app which is developed with MERN stack.

WORK EXPERIENCE

QuellxCode.com

Internship | Aug, 2021 - Oct, 2021

• During the summer of 2021, I join QuellxCode as an intern, where I work as front-end developer. And polish my skills in HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, ReactJS.

Online work

Freelancing | July, 2021 - present

 In the lockdown when everybody was curious about what will be next that time I explore online life. how and which platforms allow us to provide our skills to people who need them. And then I started freelancing on a different platforms mostly on Fiverr and Upwork

SKILLS SUMMARY

REACTJS HTML/CSS BOOSTRAP JAVASCRIPT MaterialUI TalwindCSS BACK END NodeJS, ExpressJS DATABASE MySQL MongoDB

SOFT SKILLS

Time managementProblem solvingSelf motivatedTeam work

TOOLS & SOFTWARE

- ✓ Git/Github
 ✓ VS code
 ✓ Intellij Idea
 ✓ Postman
 ✓ Enterprise Architure
 ✓ Visual Studio
- ✓ Photshop & Illustrator ✓ Figma✓ Wordpress✓ Asana

PROJECTS

WEB APP

- A portfolio website that is created in MERN stack development and it's my personal portfolio website. I know you are not confused at the front end because it is clear cut but your question will be for the backend where and why you used it. Portfolio and Testimonial section is dynamic we can add portfolio and testimonial from the front end by specific link because it's more convenient for me instead of adding to the code and then pushing then deploying etc, because its a little bit time-consuming and also I need laptop every time now I can add new testimonial and portfolio from the mobile phone. Rather than I use 2 other main libraries swiperJS for sliders, EmailJs to get form fill messages, and some animations to make them more attractive.
 - [DEPLOYED] https://mujtaba-ali.vercel.app/
 - (Front-end) https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/Mujtaba-Ali
 - (Back-end) https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/MyCV-backend
- A MERN stack memories web application where users can add posts with title, creator, different tags, and image. And It will show instantly then users can perform action on it like he/she can like the post and delete the post etc.
 - [DEPLOYED] https://eloquent-beignet-f03ed6.netlify.app/
 - (Front-end) https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/Memories-MERN-stack-FRONTEND
 - (Back-end) https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/Memories-MERN-stack-BACKEND
- POS Web application simple crud operations where admin can add new user, delete user, Update user and View user list. I create front-end in ReactJS and Backend in SpringBoot(JAVA) with MySQL database.
 - (DEPLOYED) https://pos-mujtaba4li.vercel.app/
 - (Front-end) https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/Point-of-sale-frontend REACTJS
 - (Back-end) https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/Point-of-sale-Backend SPRINGBOOT
- Our FYP is a "No Poverty" donation app, Where donors and the needy are users and they need to register themself as users. Then we created an Admin dashboard that use to approve, decline, block, and unblock the users. Also use to add, delete categories of donations and show statistics of the app. After successfully registering donors can be able to donate things and the needy can able avail them.
 - [DEPLOYED] https://admin-dashboard-fyp.vercel.app/dashboard
 - (GitHub)
 https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/Admin-dashboard-FYP

- A beautiful E-commerce website, which is created in the most popular CMS WordPress. I use the bi-language plugin to translate the whole website into french because this client belongs to France. This is one of my best WordPress websites.
 - [DEPLOYED] http://jadidcreation.com/

IOT PROJECT

- I created the Smart Parking System as a semester project with Arduino UNO and with IR sensors to detect the object and then they pass the signal to Arduino then It displays a message on LCD that the car is parked on the slot (1,2,3....) and also LCD displays message where the slot is available where the slot is unavailable. If parking is full the barrier will not open and show the message on the LCD parking is full.
 - [Demo] https://vimeo.com/740587964

DESKTOP APPLICATION

- I created the Grocery Store Management System desktop application as a semester project. In which login base where admin and cashier login is to be used and they act accordingly. Admin can perform full CRUD operation. He can add, delete, view, and update the cashier. Similarly, the cashier can perform his actions such as adding, deleting updating, and viewing items, etc.
 - (Full Application) https://github.com/Mujtaba4li/GS-management-system-DESKTOP-APP